<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creating Place for Family</title>
    <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Creating Place for Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:13:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in public services must be Darwinian</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</guid>
      <description>How do you tear down an oppressive system? Creatively. Another name for innovation is creative destruction. By pioneering a better way, innovators can undermine what existed before.
Peeling apart the concepts of policy innovation (trying something new) and program evaluation (rigorous tests of what works) helps us see how they operate differently and serve different purposes. Policy innovators try something new, while program evaluators legitimize existing practices.
For anybody with extreme views of a public service&amp;mdash;like abolishing child protective services&amp;mdash;the goal should be to create such compelling alternatives that program evaluators cannot ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Income Supports and Local Economies</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/income-supports-and-local-economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/income-supports-and-local-economies/</guid>
      <description>When the US gives money to another country, there’s often a string attached – it can only be used to buy from America. Similarly, federal contracts commonly include a “buy American” clause. This way, the money serves a double purpose of helping the recipient and supporting American industry.
A polar opposite story is the growth of Walmart in the 1980s and 1990s. Groups of local merchants would often organize to try and prevent Walmart from moving into a town and destroying them all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build the Benedict Option in New Wine Skin</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/benedict-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/benedict-option/</guid>
      <description>Restoration of consciously European Christian tradition in America is fundamentally self contradictory.
America has millions of the world’s poor and strangers knocking at its door. The reasons why are complex, but they boil down to the economic success of our society and the history of colonialism. Immigrants bring their own culture when they arrive. Solutions to preserve the power of European culture within America&amp;mdash;or communities within America, more realistically&amp;mdash;require a combination of exclusion and cultural “Euro-washing” of non-Western newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Unschooling</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/on-unschooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/on-unschooling/</guid>
      <description>I’m reading a book about post-secondary unschooling, Hacking Your Education: Ditch the Lectures, Save Tens of Thousands, and Learn More Than Your Peers Ever Will by Dale Stephens.
As an education researcher, I see an academic degree as an institution’s stamp of approval. The school is willing to tell the world that you know something or are capable of something. If they are wrong about you, it’ll hurt their reputation. To curate a group of students who know that thing (whatever it is), schools usually need to teach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risky Home Equity in Mobile-Home Parks...and Ways to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</guid>
      <description>Math expressions unfortunately don&amp;rsquo;t appear correctly on my website. I&amp;rsquo;ll work on getting that straight here.
Introduction Owners of mobile homes in mobile-home parks have a unique risk structure. Their homes are built on top of a wheeled trailer that can be towed. However, moving a “mobile” home costs a significant share of the home’s resale value and risks damage to the home. Eighty five percent of mobile homes are never moved from their initial placement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pool Your Student Loans to Build a Frat House</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</guid>
      <description>This article imagines how an organization could raise capital for real estate to house college students by pooling students&amp;rsquo; access to guaranteed government loans. It is inspired by the Korean system of Jeonse.
From Wikipedia,
&amp;ldquo;Jeonse (전세), also known as Key Money Deposit or Key Money, is a real estate term unique to South Korea that refers to the way apartments are leased. Instead of paying monthly rent, a renter will make a lump-sum deposit on a rental space, at anywhere from 50% to 80% of the market value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Take Over (a Small Corner of) the World</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the easiest way to secure housing for a community of like-minded individuals with a shared purpose? This post compares the money required to (a) build such a neighborhood from scratch versus (b) orchestrate a hostile takeover of a poorly run homeowners association.
(For context, much of my grad school work was about homeowners associations, or HOAs.)
Option A: Gain political control of an existing common interest housing development, governed by an HOA:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
