<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creating Place for Family</title>
    <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Creating Place for Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 23:13:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Think about the Predicted AI Tsunami</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/the_coming_wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/the_coming_wave/</guid>
      <description>The founder of Google DeepMind wrote a book projecting 20 years into the future. The Coming Wave (2023) by Mustafa Suleyman. He identifies AI and synthetic biology as the two big technological trends to watch. They push from two sides at the same end of creating intelligent life or very near imitations of it. Humans become less special, less homogenous, and more powerful.
The book is convincing that AI and synthetic biology will change a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in public services must be Darwinian</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</guid>
      <description>How do you tear down an oppressive system? Creatively. Another name for innovation is creative destruction. By pioneering a better way, innovators can undermine what existed before.
Peeling apart the concepts of policy innovation (trying something new) and program evaluation (rigorous tests of what works) helps us see how they operate differently and serve different purposes. Policy innovators try something new, while program evaluators legitimize existing practices.
For anybody with extreme views of a public service&amp;mdash;like abolishing child protective services&amp;mdash;the goal should be to create such compelling alternatives that program evaluators cannot ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Income Supports and Local Economies</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/income-supports-and-local-economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/income-supports-and-local-economies/</guid>
      <description>When the US gives money to another country, there’s often a string attached&amp;mdash;it can only be used to buy from America. Similarly, federal contracts commonly include a “buy American” clause. This way, the money serves a double purpose of helping the recipient and supporting American industry.
A polar opposite story is the growth of Walmart in the 1980s and 1990s. Groups of local merchants would often organize to try and prevent Walmart from moving into a town and destroying them all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Your Happiness</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/price-of-your-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/price-of-your-happiness/</guid>
      <description>“Moderation in everything” is a central guiding truth in life. Your first bite of a big meal is tastier than your last bite. This concept is called the law of diminishing marginal utility because it’s so often true.
“The difference between men and boys is the price of their toys.” –Malcolm Forbes
Real world studies back up the idea that each additional bit of consumption adds less to your happiness. The richer people are, the more extra money is required to make them happier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Logic of the Child Welfare System</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/logic-of-cps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/logic-of-cps/</guid>
      <description>The design and operation of Child Protective Services (CPS) is a topic often shrouded in pain and emotion, with big risks at play. This essay aims to take a dispassionate step back and survey the incentives that shape CPS, as part of the justice system, and how that system interacts with child and parent wellbeing.
Overview As a starting point, I assert that society chooses some minimum standard of care for children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creatures of Habit</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/creatures-of-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/creatures-of-habit/</guid>
      <description>Activities can be thought of as habit forming&amp;mdash;even addictive&amp;mdash;when their value today becomes greater the more one has done them in the past. Many of our behaviors exhibit this sort of momentum, including good ones like hand washing and bad ones like substance abuse.
Habits tie our past, current, and future selves together.
When designing a nurturing environment for families, habits cannot be ignored. The baggage that people bring with them to a community will influence how each person acts there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Alters the Marginal Cost of Meaningful Relationship</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/marginal-costs-of-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/marginal-costs-of-relationship/</guid>
      <description>Keep reading for a very wonky look at how a hybrid world threatens relationship building and what to do about it. This post needs work still, but it&amp;rsquo;s a start.
Decisions are made at the margin. That is, conditional on circumstances. When conditions change, marginal costs can be altered dramatically. I’ll pay more for a cup of water when lost in the desert than at home. I don’t plan to visit the Louvre tonight, but I might if I were already in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essays on Adapting to a Hybrid Life</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/hybrid-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/hybrid-life/</guid>
      <description>I live a hybrid life, my attention alternating between physical reality and the virtual world. My brain integrates both experiences, but an observer only understands the physical half. In my kids&amp;rsquo; and wife&amp;rsquo;s eyes, I&amp;rsquo;m switched on or off, accessible or buried in my tech.
I have no plans to quit the internet. In fact, I’ll probably use it more and more as the virtual world grows and improves every day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curated Living Packages for Low Income Households</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/leveled-consumption-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/leveled-consumption-packages/</guid>
      <description>What lifestyle package could be sold for a family living near the poverty level?
Adam Neumann, the founder of WeWork, has moved on from offices to homes. He is offering wrap-around lifestyle packages that include housing, recreation, meals, laundry, and more. The bet is that people will value the simplicity of accepting somebody else’s curated consumption package&amp;mdash;and that bulk buying will make it enough cheaper to overcome the added coordination costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet’s Creative Destruction of Church</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/internet-church-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/internet-church-destruction/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is the most destructive force of our time. That&amp;rsquo;s because inventions that create the most…also destroy the most, if you listen to Schumpeter’s theory of Creative Destruction. To see what is being destroyed, look toward what the Internet provides. It delivers information. For communication, entertainment, learning, or anything else. Any institution in our society that provides information is at risk of being edged out.
That’s the postal service, newspapers, Blockbuster Video, libraries, schools…and church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ugly Questions About Family</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/ugly-family-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/ugly-family-questions/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes practicality demands answers to ugly questions from academia. Regulators make decisions about risk based on a dollar value of death. Military planners contemplate apocalyptic destruction as a strategy to keep peace. When we shirk answering these ugly but necessary questions, people suffer.
Government policies that separate children from negligent or abusive parents raise these types of ugly questions. Probing the limits of children’s innocence and love for their parents feels profane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Building Church</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/thoughts-on-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/thoughts-on-church/</guid>
      <description>Church is a community of people practicing Christianity together.1 In community, there exists an idea of thick vs thin. A thicker community is one that is more connected; its members interact more frequently and share more important ties in their lives. One can imagine a church community as a ball or a planet, ranging from the “thickest” most involved members at the dense core to occasional visitors in the outer atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build the Benedict Option in New Wine Skin</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/benedict-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/benedict-option/</guid>
      <description>Restoration of consciously European Christian tradition in America is fundamentally self contradictory.
America has millions of the world’s poor and strangers knocking at its door. The reasons why are complex, but they boil down to the economic success of our society and the history of colonialism. Immigrants bring their own culture when they arrive. Solutions to preserve the power of European culture within America&amp;mdash;or communities within America, more realistically&amp;mdash;require a combination of exclusion and cultural “Euro-washing” of non-Western newcomers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing the Right Crowd to the Mission</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/selection-for-the-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/selection-for-the-mission/</guid>
      <description>Any organization draws a particular crowd. Companies that want strivers demand long hours. Restaurants that want a fancy atmosphere might require men to wear a jacket. Churches that want young parishioners hire young staff and trendy musicians.
A few ugly examples:
Environments with high-trust access to children draw abusers. Churches that offer comfortable services and demand nothing attract and encourage shallow Christians. Markets for goods whose quality is hard to inspect&amp;mdash;like snake oil and education&amp;mdash;draw fraudsters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Science for the Bottom Half</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/social-science-for-the-other-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/social-science-for-the-other-half/</guid>
      <description>I’ve opted for focus on the bottom 50% of wage earners as a useful rule of thumb. Free-market capitalism serves the majority well but leaves many people on the sidelines. The task for any capitalist with empathy is to intervene in the economy with a light touch. Help the poor without ruining the game for everybody. It’s an old, centrist approach in American politics: Pro-growth Progressivism from one direction, Compassionate Conservatism on the other side.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Peer Effects in Education for Equity</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/peer-effects-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/peer-effects-equity/</guid>
      <description>In education, “peer effects” refer to the ways that classmates affect each other’s education. Keeping other important factors like teacher quality and classroom size constant, the level and behavior of classmates clearly influence a child’s learning. There are many studies showing that peer effects are real and how they operate. They mainly affirm the common sense saying that “iron sharpens iron.”
Parents are aware of educational peer effects, and it drives what schools they choose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live better with less money in a big household</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/big-efficient-households/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/big-efficient-households/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for ways to cope with being broke and raising children, living together with more people is a time-tested method. Household sizes have been falling since America&amp;rsquo;s founding as we got richer. Rich European countries with old populations have the smallest households, while poorer countries with many children have the largest households, according to Wikipedia.
It costs around $18,000 per year to raise a child with a middle-class lifestyle in the US.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generational Poverty - Help the Chicken Laying Eggs</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/chicken-or-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/chicken-or-egg/</guid>
      <description>Poverty is a chicken-or-egg problem. When is the best stage in the human lifecycle at which to intervene to break cycles of poverty? Is it better to help adults or children?
In Inequality in America, James Heckman convincingly argues that programs should be squarely focused on wellbeing of young children aged 0-5. If early childhood is the most impactful period of development&amp;mdash;where poverty programs have the highest ROI&amp;mdash;and funding is limited, nearly all poverty assistance funding should be directed to early childhood programs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Unschooling</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/on-unschooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/books/on-unschooling/</guid>
      <description>I’m reading a book about post-secondary unschooling, Hacking Your Education: Ditch the Lectures, Save Tens of Thousands, and Learn More Than Your Peers Ever Will by Dale Stephens.
As an education researcher, I see an academic degree as an institution’s stamp of approval. The school is willing to tell the world that you know something or are capable of something. If they are wrong about you, it’ll hurt their reputation. To curate a group of students who know that thing (whatever it is), schools usually need to teach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebundling Community College</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/rebundling-community-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/rebundling-community-college/</guid>
      <description>Any school offers a bundle of complimentary services and attracts partners. For colleges, the anchor is teaching undergraduate students. Undergraduate tuition provides funding for graduate students and professors&amp;rsquo; research, who teach the classes. When students live on or near campus, there&amp;rsquo;s an industry to provide housing and meals that bolster the student experiences. Specialized counseling, medical, and financial aid services aim to help students successfully finish their degree. Athletics programs provide entertainment and brand awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Welfare Kingdom for 20 Somethings</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/welfare-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/welfare-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>SZA - 20 Something Framing early adulthood There&amp;rsquo;s a typical arc in an adult&amp;rsquo;s earnings over their lifetime. We start out broke at age 18, before our earnings gradually increase until late career. It&amp;rsquo;s a normal process.
When we conceptualize poverty, people typically think about lifetime earnings, although government policy only accounts for current earnings. People with low lifetime earnings normally have flatter earnings profiles. They never gain much education, and their earnings don&amp;rsquo;t increase much as they age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting Small</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/starting-small/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/starting-small/</guid>
      <description>What’s the smallest scale imaginable to foster healthy growth of young adults? What&amp;rsquo;s the path to growth?
Participate in a home matching online marketplace as an intermediary. Rent a home and sublet to subjects. Design rules for subjects’ cooperation. Provide a minimal set of services like back-up childcare, tutoring, academic advising, job searching, government benefits and tax advice, etc. Recruit more established adults to serve as mentors. Lend reputation by helping get subjects jobs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insuring Lives of Service</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/insuring-lives-of-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/insuring-lives-of-service/</guid>
      <description>Christians are called to live in the moment. To save up treasures in heaven, not on Earth. To trust God. But we are also not to be irresponsible and an undue burden on each other. It’s foolish to trust too fully in men, even if they profess trust in Christ. Failing to plan is planning to fail.
How do we design lives of service to God and neighbors without misplacing too much trust in humans?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commune Dreaming</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/commune-dreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/commune-dreaming/</guid>
      <description>I dream of starting an intentional living community. For those who know me, “the Commune.” Since 2017, when I first started blathering about the Commune, the idea has remained slippery. It’s a loose collection of shifting goals that don&amp;rsquo;t accurately reflect a commune, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a better name.
So I’m starting a collection of related blog posts to help myself and others understand the vision, and maybe realize it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empathy</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/empathy/</guid>
      <description>One of the hardest ideas to wrestle with is that there are 8 billion other people living in this world with the same depth of experience as me. They each have the same depth of feeling as me. Each person experiences quiet thoughts and has clever inside jokes with their friends.
I have no insight into their lives. I don’t know them. I don’t control them. I am insignificant.
There’s a self-aggrandizing power trip in planning to change the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Families, an Endowed Social Enterprise (unfinished)</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/supported-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/supported-families/</guid>
      <description>Target populations:
Community college students Young parents + kids at risk of CPS involvement because of poverty Goals for residents:
Earn online degrees or certificates, with completion rates in line with public research universities Vocational training and start businesses Build savings Build healthy families Features
Pooled household services like laundry and basic food Pooled childcare, augmented with parenting training Shared services for Internet, phone, etc. Heavy surveillance for child safety and a healthy environment (drug free) Educational support services for online college and for kids Placement with local employers Entrepreneurship incubator Minimize need for ongoing funding beyond initial endowment of land and buildings so that it&amp;rsquo;s extensible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risky Home Equity in Mobile-Home Parks...and Ways to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</guid>
      <description>Math expressions unfortunately don&amp;rsquo;t appear correctly on my website. I&amp;rsquo;ll work on getting that straight here.
Introduction Owners of mobile homes in mobile-home parks have a unique risk structure. Their homes are built on top of a wheeled trailer that can be towed. However, moving a “mobile” home costs a significant share of the home’s resale value and risks damage to the home. Eighty five percent of mobile homes are never moved from their initial placement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Price of Parenting and Foster Parenting (unfinished)</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/who-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/cps/who-parents/</guid>
      <description>In Rosen’s paper, the theory is that companies simultaneously pay a price for labor, and workers pay a shadow price for a job. The shadow price that workers pay for a job is their maximum earnings potential minus their actual earnings. Workers can be excluded from certain types of jobs if the job’s shadow price exceeds their earnings potential.
This idea seems relevant to people’s decision to parent and provide foster care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Focus on the Family</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/new-focus-on-the-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/new-focus-on-the-family/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, Dad liked to listen to radio programs from an organization called Focus on the Family. It&amp;rsquo;s a Christian media group centered on the premise of &amp;ldquo;helping families thrive.&amp;rdquo; I always loved that goal. Anyone with a family knows how hard family life can be!
Unfortunately, Focus on the Family preaches a narrow vision of how family should look. Their focus is promoting the health of traditional married couples with children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pool Your Student Loans to Build a Frat House</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</guid>
      <description>This article imagines how an organization could raise capital for real estate to house college students by pooling students&amp;rsquo; access to guaranteed government loans. It is inspired by the Korean system of Jeonse.
From Wikipedia,
&amp;ldquo;Jeonse (전세), also known as Key Money Deposit or Key Money, is a real estate term unique to South Korea that refers to the way apartments are leased. Instead of paying monthly rent, a renter will make a lump-sum deposit on a rental space, at anywhere from 50% to 80% of the market value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government Help to Raise Families Above the Poverty Line...but No Higher</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/eitc-marginal-tax-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/eitc-marginal-tax-rate/</guid>
      <description>(This article was originally posted on the National Research Center on Hispanic Children and Families&amp;rsquo; blog in April 2016, where I interned. Their blog has since disappeared so I&amp;rsquo;m re-posting here. It was originally titled &amp;ldquo;Looking at Tax Time for Near Poor Hispanic Families&amp;rdquo;.)
Mariela, a hypothetical single mom with two kids, just filed her 2015 federal taxes. Her adjusted gross income (AGI) this year was $25,000. She’s receiving a tax return of just over $4,000 thanks, largely, to the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Take Over (a Small Corner of) the World</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the easiest way to secure housing for a community of like-minded individuals with a shared purpose? This post compares the money required to (a) build such a neighborhood from scratch versus (b) orchestrate a hostile takeover of a poorly run homeowners association.
(For context, much of my grad school work was about homeowners associations, or HOAs.)
Option A: Gain political control of an existing common interest housing development, governed by an HOA:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving to the Best Neighborhood</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/best-neighborhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/best-neighborhood/</guid>
      <description>When you buy or rent a home, you&amp;rsquo;re choosing more than the home. You get proximity to shops and parks, access to schools, and public services like police and fire protection. Perhaps most importantly, you choose your neighbors.
Our neighbors can affect us in many ways. Neighbors determine local crime, whether grocery stores invest in the area, and how our kids&amp;rsquo; peers behave. Economists call these externalities - side effects on us that our neighbors didn&amp;rsquo;t intend and don&amp;rsquo;t think much about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Bad Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/avoiding-bad-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/avoiding-bad-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>Somebody asked Jesus, &amp;ldquo;Who is my neighbor?&amp;rdquo; To that, Jesus replied with the parable of the Good Samaritan, who helped a wounded man he found on the side of the road.
Many of us are one step ahead of Jesus. We have moved to safe neighborhoods where junkies don&amp;rsquo;t mug poor strangers for us to find. We use &amp;ldquo;walkability scores&amp;rdquo; in our GPS directions to help us avoid those lonely, dangerous sidewalks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Do with Displaced Workers, Old Folks, and Children?</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/displaced-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/philosophy/displaced-workers/</guid>
      <description>Jim, one of my childhood mentors, was a copy machine repairman. I don’t know his full story, but I know he got shot in the Vietnam War. Every Sunday, he carried a tote filled with candy to our church and distributed his loot liberally if we kids could recite Bible verses. He was a hero.
Jim started repairing Xerox machines in the 1970s or 1980s when they were high-value machines, mechanically complicated, and easily broken.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
