<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Creating Place for Family</title>
    <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Creating Place for Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:13:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in public services must be Darwinian</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/policy-innovation-is-darwinian/</guid>
      <description>How do you tear down an oppressive system? Creatively. Another name for innovation is creative destruction. By pioneering a better way, innovators can undermine what existed before.
Peeling apart the concepts of policy innovation (trying something new) and program evaluation (rigorous tests of what works) helps us see how they operate differently and serve different purposes. Policy innovators try something new, while program evaluators legitimize existing practices.
For anybody with extreme views of a public service&amp;mdash;like abolishing child protective services&amp;mdash;the goal should be to create such compelling alternatives that program evaluators cannot ignore them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Income Supports and Local Economies</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/income-supports-and-local-economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/posts/income-supports-and-local-economies/</guid>
      <description>When the US gives money to another country, there’s often a string attached – it can only be used to buy from America. Similarly, federal contracts commonly include a “buy American” clause. This way, the money serves a double purpose of helping the recipient and supporting American industry.
A polar opposite story is the growth of Walmart in the 1980s and 1990s. Groups of local merchants would often organize to try and prevent Walmart from moving into a town and destroying them all.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
