<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Schemes on Creating Place for Family</title>
    <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Schemes on Creating Place for Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:22:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curated Living Packages for Low Income Households</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/leveled-consumption-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/leveled-consumption-packages/</guid>
      <description>What lifestyle package could be sold for a family living near the poverty level?
Adam Neumann, the founder of WeWork, has moved on from offices to homes. He is offering wrap-around lifestyle packages that include housing, recreation, meals, laundry, and more. The bet is that people will value the simplicity of accepting somebody else’s curated consumption package&amp;mdash;and that bulk buying will make it enough cheaper to overcome the added coordination costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebundling Community College</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/rebundling-community-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/rebundling-community-college/</guid>
      <description>Any school offers a bundle of complimentary services and attracts partners. For colleges, the anchor is teaching undergraduate students. Undergraduate tuition provides funding for graduate students and professors&amp;rsquo; research, who teach the classes. When students live on or near campus, there&amp;rsquo;s an industry to provide housing and meals that bolster the student experiences. Specialized counseling, medical, and financial aid services aim to help students successfully finish their degree. Athletics programs provide entertainment and brand awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting Small</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/starting-small/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/starting-small/</guid>
      <description>What’s the smallest scale imaginable to foster healthy growth of young adults? What&amp;rsquo;s the path to growth?
Participate in a home matching online marketplace as an intermediary. Rent a home and sublet to subjects. Design rules for subjects’ cooperation. Provide a minimal set of services like back-up childcare, tutoring, academic advising, job searching, government benefits and tax advice, etc. Recruit more established adults to serve as mentors. Lend reputation by helping get subjects jobs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insuring Lives of Service</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/insuring-lives-of-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/insuring-lives-of-service/</guid>
      <description>Christians are called to live in the moment. To save up treasures in heaven, not on Earth. To trust God. But we are also not to be irresponsible and an undue burden on each other. It’s foolish to trust too fully in men, even if they profess trust in Christ. Failing to plan is planning to fail.
How do we design lives of service to God and neighbors without misplacing too much trust in humans?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commune Dreaming</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/commune-dreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/commune-dreaming/</guid>
      <description>I dream of starting an intentional living community. For those who know me, “the Commune.” Since 2017, when I first started blathering about the Commune, the idea has remained slippery. It’s a loose collection of shifting goals that don&amp;rsquo;t accurately reflect a commune, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a better name.
So I’m starting a collection of related blog posts to help myself and others understand the vision, and maybe realize it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported Families, an Endowed Social Enterprise (unfinished)</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/supported-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/schemes/supported-families/</guid>
      <description>Target populations:
Community college students Young parents + kids at risk of CPS involvement because of poverty Goals for residents:
Earn online degrees or certificates, with completion rates in line with public research universities Vocational training and start businesses Build savings Build healthy families Features
Pooled household services like laundry and basic food Pooled childcare, augmented with parenting training Shared services for Internet, phone, etc. Heavy surveillance for child safety and a healthy environment (drug free) Educational support services for online college and for kids Placement with local employers Entrepreneurship incubator Minimize need for ongoing funding beyond initial endowment of land and buildings so that it&amp;rsquo;s extensible.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
