<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real_estates on Creating Place for Family</title>
    <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Real_estates on Creating Place for Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:22:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Risky Home Equity in Mobile-Home Parks...and Ways to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:22:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/mobile-home-risky-equity/</guid>
      <description>Math expressions unfortunately don&amp;rsquo;t appear correctly on my website. I&amp;rsquo;ll work on getting that straight here.
Introduction Owners of mobile homes in mobile-home parks have a unique risk structure. Their homes are built on top of a wheeled trailer that can be towed. However, moving a “mobile” home costs a significant share of the home’s resale value and risks damage to the home. Eighty five percent of mobile homes are never moved from their initial placement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pool Your Student Loans to Build a Frat House</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/jeonse-frat/</guid>
      <description>This article imagines how an organization could raise capital for real estate to house college students by pooling students&amp;rsquo; access to guaranteed government loans. It is inspired by the Korean system of Jeonse.
From Wikipedia,
&amp;ldquo;Jeonse (전세), also known as Key Money Deposit or Key Money, is a real estate term unique to South Korea that refers to the way apartments are leased. Instead of paying monthly rent, a renter will make a lump-sum deposit on a rental space, at anywhere from 50% to 80% of the market value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Take Over (a Small Corner of) the World</title>
      <link>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 23:13:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wyattclarke.github.io/place-for-family/real_estate/hoa-takeover/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the easiest way to secure housing for a community of like-minded individuals with a shared purpose? This post compares the money required to (a) build such a neighborhood from scratch versus (b) orchestrate a hostile takeover of a poorly run homeowners association.
(For context, much of my grad school work was about homeowners associations, or HOAs.)
Option A: Gain political control of an existing common interest housing development, governed by an HOA:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
